<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.7.4">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2019-02-08T19:48:53-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/</id><title type="html">Jarrett Fuller</title><subtitle>Designer, Writer, Podcaster</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Conan, Late Night Talk Shows, and Multi-platform comedy</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/conan/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Conan, Late Night Talk Shows, and Multi-platform comedy" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/conan</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/conan/">&lt;h3 id=&quot;1-apartment-103&quot;&gt;1. Apartment 103&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My college roommates and I were close. There were four of us — Ryan, Eric, Dustin, and me — and during the two years we lived in Apartment 103, we did everything together. We ate dinner together, around the table, like a family. We bought a Christmas tree together and made stockings for each other. We went to movies and watched every season of &lt;em&gt;The Wire&lt;/em&gt; and &lt;em&gt;Dexter&lt;/em&gt;. That apartment was the first place outside of my childhood house that felt like home.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;It was the end of the semester and Ryan and Dustin had already gone home for the holidays; only Eric and I were left. He had made eggnog earlier in the day (as you do) and at 11:30pm, we sat in front of the television to watch Conan O’Brien’s final night as host of &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt;. I had just started getting into late night talk shows and was obsessed with the &lt;em&gt;Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; debacle. Here’s a quick refresher: in 2004, Jay Leno announced he was retiring from &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; and handing the show over to Conan O’Brien, then the lost of &lt;em&gt;Late Night&lt;/em&gt;. At the beginning of 2009, Conan took over and the ratings dropped. NBC, in a panic, didn’t want to give Conan the time to find his footing, and after a mere nine months, announced they were moving the &lt;em&gt;Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; back a half hour and giving Leno a new show at his old time. Conan quit and the network gave Leno his old show back. In the ten years since, Leno retired again, and every other talk show got a new host. Conan found a new home on TBS where he’s been chugging away, doing his thing, quietly becoming the longest running talk show host of the current era.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Conan was never my &lt;em&gt;favorite&lt;/em&gt; host — Letterman always held that spot for me, and now it’s Stephen Colbert of the current lineup &lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:1&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:1&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; — but I always found him the most &lt;em&gt;interesting&lt;/em&gt; of the bunch. Certainly more interesting than Leno and Fallon, and I was sad to see him lose the show&lt;sup id=&quot;fnref:2&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;#fn:2&quot; class=&quot;footnote&quot;&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;. Watching that final show with Eric — the images of Conan on &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; set, playing guitar with Max Weinberg and Will Ferrell as the credits rolled — is one of my strongest memories of late night talk shows, and certainly a highlight from Apartment 103.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;2-were-trying-to-be-anarchists&quot;&gt;2. “We’re Trying to be Anarchists”&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/images/conan-half-hour.jpg&quot; /&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;figcaption&gt;Text&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Late last year, Conan announced that his now almost decade old TBS show would move to a half-hour format. The change would allow him to try new things on the show while also expanding his popular digital presence. Over the last few months, while the show was on hiatus, Conan launched a podcast, went on tour, and announced a new website that will archive every episode of Conan’s shows. The shorter show would allow Conan to do more of what he does well — the travel shows and web exclusives like Clueless Gamer have proven surprisingly successful. By reducing the run-time for his TBS show, he’d have more time to devote to these extracurricular experiments while also easily playing with what the show itself can be.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;On the new &lt;em&gt;Conan&lt;/em&gt;, the desk is gone, the suits are gone, the band is gone. The set has been rebuilt, now just a small stage that can be reconfigured depending on what they are doing. Andy Richter is still there on the side of the stage. And Conan is still Conan. In the first few episodes I watched, the show felt largely the same, just shorter. As Rob Harvilla wrote for &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.theringer.com/tv/2019/1/23/18194206/conan-obrien-return-half-hour-tbs-episode-1&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;The Ringer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;, it was “addition by subtraction”. The show obviously looked new and everything felt looser but the structure was still there: a monologue, a sketch or prerecorded  bit, and an interview.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No show knows what it is in the first episode; or even the first year. The mistake NBC made in 2009 was jumping the gun, not giving Conan the time and space he needed to settle in and make the show his. It’s hard to remember now, but Colbert’s first year on the &lt;em&gt;Late Show&lt;/em&gt; was rocky; with constant rumors that CBS wanted to swap his timeslot with James Cordon. And of course when Conan took over for Letterman back in 1993, he was rumored to be on a week-to-week contract. We shouldn’t judge the new show by one week of episodes but it feels underwhelming after months of hearing how the new run-time would allow the show to be more experimental. Perhaps they are still easing their way into it, perhaps they still aren’t sure what they can do. But for this new show to be truly exciting, it needs to get weirder. Conan needs to lean into what makes &lt;em&gt;Conan&lt;/em&gt; Conan. There’s still a lot of potential here.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Every time a new host takes over a franchise, there is a chance to mix up the standard talk show format popularized by Johnny Carson — there’s the monologue, a desk bit or a skit, two guests or three guests, and a musical act or stand up set — but each reincarnation is largely more of the same. Sure, Colbert made the monologue his own, where they often clock in well over ten minutes. Seth Meyers performs his monologue behind the desk. James Corden and Jimmy Fallon focus more on games and viral-style videos but it’s still just a white guy in a suit sitting behind a desk telling jokes and talking to people. It’s a design problem, really: how do you work within the constraints of the format while making something your own? “We’re trying to be anarchists, but I’m trying to be a good boy and do a good job for the network,” Conan told &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2019/01/14/arts/television/conan-obrien-tbs-show-reboot-half-hour.html&quot;&gt;Dave Itzoff of &lt;em&gt;The New York Times&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. What he’s engaged in now, he said, “is this gradual progression toward me making the job fit me more — what do I like?”&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That’s the tension with late night talk shows — especially with established francises like &lt;em&gt;Tonight&lt;/em&gt; or &lt;em&gt;Late Night&lt;/em&gt;: how do you honor the form that’s been honed down over the last three decades while creating something new. Conan, perhaps more than any other late night host, has pushed himself up against that dominant form to question what else it could be. Sometimes, like Colbert or Seth Meyers, you find ways to work within in the system. But for Conan, the best way forward, I think, is to throw away that tradition and making something wholly his own. With TBS, he found a partner that gives him the space (and time) to try new things and make the show more like him. But the other, more important, question is: how central is the &lt;em&gt;show&lt;/em&gt; to Conan’s new output.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;3-building-your-own-printing-press&quot;&gt;3. Building Your Own Printing Press&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ten years ago, around the same time I was watching the final episodes of Conan’s &lt;em&gt;Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; with Eric, I started to get interesting in media distribution. The iPad would come out a few months later and this was when the first paywalls were being erected around newspaper websites. As someone who was always publishing little things online, I was excited by the potential and increasingly low-bar to entry. I wrote an essay for the now-defunct blog I kept through college on these changes and wondered out loud whether Conan even needed a new network. The essay — titled “Building Your Own Printing Press” — is no longer online but used the A.J. Liebling’s popular aphorism, “Freedom of the press is only free for those to own a printing press” as my starting point. The internet, I argued, gave everyone their own printing press. Conan was my prime example. Here’s the key paragraph:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Under his exit contract with NBC, Conan O’Brien is unable to join another network until after September 1. So what will he do until then? Mr. O’Brien finds himself with a lot of free time and a lot of cash which make for the terrific combination to fully embrace independent media. It would be extremely easy for Conan to launch a new show without any network, contract, and deals and it could be all online, the way his fans watch him anyway. He would get to do his show, the way he wants to do it and not have to worry about networks giving him a hard time. The way we are consuming our media is changing and it’s about time the distribution caught up.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;p&gt;That was in 2009 — I was an overly optimistic (and arrogant) college student — and I realize now how much harder that would have been a decade ago. But now, in 2019, it is possible. YouTube stars are a thing. Instagram influencers is a term we now say without flinching. And it’s exactly what Conan is now doing. Conan and TBS have entered a deeper partnership and are careful to continually point out the “show” isn’t the only part of that partnership. There’s already a podcast and a recently finished tour and I imagine we can expect more of that. Under the new contract, Conan can record as much as he wants each day and only owes TBS a half-hour. The rest can go online, or in any other place it fits. The format I wished for ten years ago probably wasn’t financially possible then but it certainly is now.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This raises the question: how important is the TBS show to this new &lt;em&gt;multi-platform comedy empire&lt;/em&gt; (ugh)? If anything, the show has been reduced to just another spoke in the wheel. By devoting less energy specifically to the show, each component can shift more freely. It’s here that Conan is truly subverting the late night form.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This is what I couldn’t quite reconcile ten years ago: Conan is on TV but his fans aren’t watching TV. The late night talk show is an archaic format; a relic from another era. Appointment viewing isn’t how people watch television anymore. (Think about how many times Netflix has tried to get into this area. So far they’ve been unable to crack it because it goes against Netflix’s whole model.) These shows are increasingly being watching in bits and pieces on YouTube the next morning. I’ve never seen an entire episode of &lt;em&gt;Late Night with Seth Meyers&lt;/em&gt; but I’ve watched every single one of his &lt;em&gt;A Closer Look&lt;/em&gt; segments.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Instead of prioritizing the show, Conan gives everything — the show, YouTube, his podcast — equal weight. It’s appealing to both sides of the generational divide, both packaged for TV and distributed across the web. You can watch it as a traditional talk show or online in short clips. While late night viewership decrease on television, they are increasing online. Much like newspapers and magazines struggled to get their content online in the early days of the web, so to are television networks still figuring out how to go digital. For many of these other shows, segments are clipped for YouTube or there’s a separate team making original content for online venues (that often feels like it’s separate from the show.) The other networks and hosts can take a cue from Conan and TBS, fully integrating the two, giving equal weight to both sides. As Conan said in another interview, perhaps in five years people won’t even notice that the “show” — in the traditional sense that we think about it now — is completely gone. Under this new model, it’s not impossible that ever-so-slowly, everything moves online.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Content-wise, Conan will find his footing within the new show. These first few weeks are testing the waters, being a beginner all over again. But it’s important to not overlook how much he’s already trying something new. This openness to different media platforms is, I think, the future of the genre. At least, it’s the future I wanted when I was sitting there in Apartment 103. I haven’t sat down at 11:30 to watch &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; since.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;footnotes&quot;&gt;
  &lt;ol&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:1&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’d also put Dick Cavett on my list right along Letterman, but his show never felt connected to the big four: Tonight, Late Night, Late Show, and Late Late Show. It always seemed like he always was doing his own thing. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:1&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li id=&quot;fn:2&quot;&gt;
      &lt;p&gt;I’ve long held a theory about the Tonight Show. Letterman famously wanted it in the nineties after Carson retired — and Carson supposedly saw Letterman as his rightful heir — but the show went to frequent guest host Jay Leno. When Leno retired &lt;em&gt;again&lt;/em&gt; in 2013, Jimmy Fallon took it over and is the current host. &lt;em&gt;The Tonight Show&lt;/em&gt; is a brand name — that’s the &lt;em&gt;popular&lt;/em&gt; show. It has to be generic, inoffensive, appeal to the most people. Letterman wouldn’t have been good on &lt;em&gt;Tonight&lt;/em&gt; — he’s too smart and too weird. Same with Conan. Leno and Fallon and can do that. They are less interesting, better at appealing to the widest audience possible. &lt;a href=&quot;#fnref:2&quot; class=&quot;reversefootnote&quot;&gt;&amp;#8617;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
    &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1. Apartment 103 My college roommates and I were close. There were four of us — Ryan, Eric, Dustin, and me — and during the two years we lived in Apartment 103, we did everything together. We ate dinner together, around the table, like a family. We bought a Christmas tree together and made stockings for each other. We went to movies and watched every season of The Wire and Dexter. That apartment was the first place outside of my childhood house that felt like home.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Journey by Mary Oliver</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/mary-oliver/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Journey by Mary Oliver" /><published>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-30T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/mary-oliver</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/mary-oliver/">&lt;p&gt;One day you finally knew&lt;br /&gt;
what you had to do, and began,&lt;br /&gt;
though the voices around you&lt;br /&gt;
kept shouting&lt;br /&gt;
their bad advice – – –&lt;br /&gt;
though the whole house&lt;br /&gt;
began to tremble&lt;br /&gt;
and you felt the old tug&lt;br /&gt;
at your ankles.&lt;br /&gt;
‘Mend my life!’&lt;br /&gt;
each voice cried.&lt;br /&gt;
But you didn’t stop.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
You knew what you had to do,&lt;br /&gt;
though the wind pried&lt;br /&gt;
with its stiff fingers&lt;br /&gt;
at the very foundations – – –&lt;br /&gt;
though their melancholy&lt;br /&gt;
was terrible. It was already late&lt;br /&gt;
enough, and a wild night,&lt;br /&gt;
and the road full of fallen&lt;br /&gt;
branches and stones.&lt;br /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
But little by little,&lt;br /&gt;
as you left their voices behind,&lt;br /&gt;
the stars began to burn&lt;br /&gt;
through the sheets of clouds,&lt;br /&gt;
and there was a new voice,
which you slowly&lt;br /&gt;
recognized as your own,&lt;br /&gt;
that kept you company&lt;br /&gt;
as you strode deeper and deeper&lt;br /&gt;
into the world,&lt;br /&gt;
determined to do&lt;br /&gt;
the only thing you could do – – – determined to save&lt;br /&gt;
the only life you could save.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Photography" /><summary type="html">One day you finally knew what you had to do, and began, though the voices around you kept shouting their bad advice – – – though the whole house began to tremble and you felt the old tug at your ankles. ‘Mend my life!’ each voice cried. But you didn’t stop. You knew what you had to do, though the wind pried with its stiff fingers at the very foundations – – – though their melancholy was terrible. It was already late enough, and a wild night, and the road full of fallen branches and stones. But little by little, as you left their voices behind, the stars began to burn through the sheets of clouds, and there was a new voice, which you slowly recognized as your own, that kept you company as you strode deeper and deeper into the world, determined to do the only thing you could do – – – determined to save the only life you could save.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Brutalist Architecture of University of California Irvine</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/uc-irvine/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Brutalist Architecture of University of California Irvine" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/uc-irvine</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/uc-irvine/">&lt;p&gt;I was in Southern California at the end of the year to spend Christmas with my wife’s family. On one especially lazy day after the holidays, we decided to visit the campus of University of California, Irvine, my wife’s alma mater. I didn’t know her in college and wanted to see where she studied undergrad, and she hadn’t been back since. I didn’t know anything about the school or campus, but when we pulled up to the main entrance, my wife turned to me and said, “Get ready for a lot of brutalism.”
[[MORE]]&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And a lot of brutalism there was! What my wife didn’t tell me — and what none of us knew — UCI is home to a collection of brutalist structures designed in 1963 by William Pereira. Pereira, an amazingly prolific architect, worked out of Los Angeles, became a professor at University of California in 1949. He designed the master community plan for the entire city of Irvine, San Francisco’s Transamerica Pyramid, UCSD’s Geisel Library, and the original buildings of the LA County Museum of Art. He is one of the few architects to make the cover of Time Magazine.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/02231f1875a048be564fa9184767b76b/tumblr_inline_pl0rrhnJ141qzwy5u_540.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The campus is designed around a central park — whose landscape architecture was inspired by Fredrich Law Olmstead — so no building would be more than a ten minute walk from any other. Pereira, a science fiction fan, wanted to create a modernist/futurist environment where every building related to the other, creating a unified style across the campus. “It was a bold plan at the time, and still is. Pereira wanted to create a sort of academic village in a wooded, hilly park.” &lt;a href=&quot;http://modernistarchitecture.blogspot.com/2015/03/uc-irvine-singular-brutalist-vision.html&quot;&gt;writes Darren Bradley, an architectural photographer&lt;/a&gt;, “At the time, it was a barren hillside of treeless cow pastures. Instead of flattening the hilly terrain with bulldozers, he created floating white concrete platforms suspended over the ground on pedestals, that would support the buildings and present them like individual sculptures on display in a giant museum sculpture garden.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/7c322d74443235d9283da178b873d0d2/tumblr_inline_pl0rdf7QfQ1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/44077ca866390c20ad0d4c10e51cc0c9/tumblr_inline_pl0rl9xS5T1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/2a20b7d9d612620a18585b0d567f79a0/tumblr_inline_pl0rdqi8un1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/7c322d74443235d9283da178b873d0d2/tumblr_inline_pl0re2BXaJ1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/548da0258578f5b3b9b8e10bcbde4260/tumblr_inline_pl0rekTFDO1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/f241ee34b5fddb8bae20ba39a529e888/tumblr_inline_pl0rl2UHgz1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/00de24183bbea63081b1e522feb218d5/tumblr_inline_pl0rluTD9U1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;In 1977, Pereira was replaced as campus architect by David Neuman, who immediately announced that he was abandoning Pereira’s careful plan. By then, modernism had fallen out of vogue and Neuman invited postmodern architects like Charles Moore, Venturi &amp;amp; Brown, and Robert A.M. Stern to design new buildings for the campus. After a building freeze construction resumed in the late eighties and continues today as the campus continues to grow. The new buildings attempt — at varying degrees of success — to bridge the styles of Pereira’s original plan and Neuman’s postmodern dreams. My favorite building of the postmodern era is probably Arthur Erickson’s McGaugh Hall — a quintessential postmodern structure that sticks out like a sore thumb in the sea of concrete but is strangely charming in its environment.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/a8366597745c8d4e983436bddc5cc8b4/tumblr_inline_pl0rexrGre1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Pereira’s legacy on the UCI campus lives on, even if not for the modernist, utopian dream he set out to plan. The campus was featured heavily in the 1977 &lt;em&gt;Conquest of the Planet of the Apes&lt;/em&gt;. As a science fiction fan, I can’t help but think Pereira would be pleased to see his work immortalized, even if it is meant to be the architecture of an oppressive ape regime.
&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/916acf4fa7d33a30517e52ed81c880ed/tumblr_inline_pl0rc3fohX1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/5263d08e6d6e11c7aab6efa7f15cd628/tumblr_inline_pl0rc96NPM1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;All photos my own, except for &lt;a href=&quot;http://modernistarchitecture.blogspot.com/2015/03/uc-irvine-singular-brutalist-vision.html&quot;&gt;Planet of the Apes screenshots&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I was in Southern California at the end of the year to spend Christmas with my wife’s family. On one especially lazy day after the holidays, we decided to visit the campus of University of California, Irvine, my wife’s alma mater. I didn’t know her in college and wanted to see where she studied undergrad, and she hadn’t been back since. I didn’t know anything about the school or campus, but when we pulled up to the main entrance, my wife turned to me and said, “Get ready for a lot of brutalism.” [[MORE]]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Austin</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/austin/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Austin" /><published>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-08T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/austin</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/austin/">&lt;p&gt;I spent the beginning of the year on a short vacation in Austin, TX. I’d never been but it’d had been a city on my list to visit for years. In between breakfast tacos and barbecue, I was most excited to see Ellsworth Kelly’s &lt;em&gt;Austin&lt;/em&gt;, a standalone structure — a temple of light — at Austin’s Blanton Museum.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Kelly, known for his color field paintings and plant drawings, designed this structure nearly thirty years ago and expected it to never be built. Thanks to generous donations and the Blanton’s organization, construction began a few months before Kelly died, in 2015, at 92. &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nytimes.com/2018/02/08/t-magazine/ellsworth-kelly-austin-last-work.html&quot;&gt;M.h. Miller wrote about its history for The New York Times earlier this year, after it opened&lt;/a&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;We visited on a rainy Wednesday, when the museum was largely quiet, and got to experience the work in solitude. The color windows cast a rainbow across the space; the rain quietly beating outside: it was, unsurprisingly, a moving experience and the highlight of my trip.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/981687d7cde3b6aa26e96773fb83a6c8/tumblr_inline_pkyxdmCIzZ1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/1c0a30c1eda22c33c629111ea389c448/tumblr_inline_pkyxe56ggH1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/be06fa55c67329f08c9bf0a073f8aa14/tumblr_inline_pkyxkl2XAp1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;https://66.media.tumblr.com/3527734f9d00a588fae5916a5a455941/tumblr_inline_pkyxec3OBX1qzwy5u_1280.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">I spent the beginning of the year on a short vacation in Austin, TX. I’d never been but it’d had been a city on my list to visit for years. In between breakfast tacos and barbecue, I was most excited to see Ellsworth Kelly’s Austin, a standalone structure — a temple of light — at Austin’s Blanton Museum.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">2018 Movies Watched</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/2018-movies-watched/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="2018 Movies Watched" /><published>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-01-07T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2019/01/2018-movies-watched</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2019/01/2018-movies-watched/">&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/5/2018	 Harry Potter and the Sorcerers Stone&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/6/2018	 Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/7/2018	 Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/13/2018	Phantom Thread&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/13/2018	Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/14/2018	Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/15/2018	Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/19/2018	Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows Part I&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/20/2018	Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows Part 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/23/2018	The Visual Language of Herbert Matter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/26/2018	A Ghost Story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/28/2018	Get Out&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/30/2018	Kumiku, The Treasure Hunter&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;1/31/2018	The Founder&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/9/2018	 David Bowie: The Last Five Years&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/13/2018	Standup for Drummers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;2/16/2018	Wonder Woman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/2/2018	 Fast and Furious&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/3/2018	 Black Panther&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/4/2018	 Where The Wild Things Are&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/10/2018	Call Me By Your Name&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/11/2018	The War Room&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/12/2018	Annihilation&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/13/2018	Jackie&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/15/2018	Gerhard Richter Painting&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/17/2018	Icarus&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/18/2018	A Wrinkle in Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/24/2018	The Death of Stalin&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/28/2018	The Zen Diaries of Garry Shandling&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/31/2018	Isle of Dogs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;3/31/2018	Atomic Blonde&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/1/2018 	Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/7/2018	 The Florida Project&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/13/2018	The Cloverfield Paradox&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/13/2018	Seeing Allread&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/14/2018	Gaga: Five Foot Two&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/19/2018	Hidden Figures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/21/2018	Carol&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/26/2018	Paterno&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/28/2018	The Rachel Divide&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;4/29/2018	A Quiet Place&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/3/2018	 Big Time&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/10/2018	Alps&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/12/2018	Faces Places&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/13/2018	Avengers: Infinity War&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/14/2018	Brad’s Status&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/15/2018	The Killing of a Sacred Deer&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/17/2018	The Fate of the Furious&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/18/2018	Ali Wong: Hard Knock Wife&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/19/2018	Guardians of the Galaxy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/20/2018	Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/22/2018	Dunkirk&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/23/2018	Dogtooth&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/26/2018	Secret Window&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/27/2018	Deadpool&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;5/28/2018	Deadpool 2&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/7/2018	 Coco&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/8/2018	 LBJ&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/9/2018 	The Final Year&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/10/2018	Solo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/11/2018	Tokyo Story&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/12/2018	Patty Cake$&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/14/2018	The Informant!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/16/2018	Blade Runner 2049&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/17/2018	Ocean’s 8&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/17/2018	Wonder Wheel&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/22/2018	Come Sunday&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/23/2018	Doctor Strange&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/24/2018	Hereditary&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/29/2018	Young Karl Marx&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/29/2018	Hannah Gatsby: Nanette&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;6/30/2018	Thor&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/2/2018	 Fahrenheit 451&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/3/2018 	Dick Cavett’s Watergate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/4/2018	 First Reformed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/4/2018	 Thor: The Dark World&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/7/2018	 Thor: Ragnarock&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/8/2018	 Sorry to Bother You&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/9/2018	 What We Do In the Shadows&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/11/2018	Boy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/14/2018	The Incredibles II&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/15/2018	Eighth Grade&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/15/2018	Marvel’s The Avengers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/18/2018	The Heretic&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/22/2018	Bo Burnham: Make Happy&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/24/2018	John Mulaney: Kid Gorgeous at Radio City&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/25/2018	Chris Rock: Tambourine&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/25/2018	The Disaster Artist&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;7/30/2018	Chisholm ‘72: Unbought &amp;amp; Unbossed&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/4/2018	A Girl Walks Home Alone At Night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/10/2018	Avengers: Age of Ultron&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/11/2018	Ant-Man&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/17/2018	Ex Machina&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/18/2018	Unsane&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/19/2018	Blackkklansman&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/19/2018	Steve Martin &amp;amp; Martin Short: A Night You Will Forget for the Rest of your Life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/20/2018	Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/21/2018	Film socialisme&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/22/2018	It&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/24/2018	Hunt for the Wilderpeople&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;8/25/2018	John McCain: For Whom the Bell Tolls&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/1/2018	 Mission: Impossible - Fallout&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/7/2018	To All the Boys I’ve Loved Before&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/9/2018	 Battle of the Sexes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/14/2018	Mother!&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/16/2018	Crazy Rich Asians&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/19/2018	Robin Williams: Come Inside My Mind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/20/2018	Loving Vincent&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;9/21/2018	Cargo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/3/2018	Suburbicon&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/5/2018	The Shape of Water&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/6/2018	Private Life&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/9/2018	The Land of Steady Habits&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/10/2018	 Yojimbo&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/11/2018	 The Seventh Seal&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/12/2018	 Landline&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;10/31/2018	 The Strangers: Prey At Night&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/4/2018	Suspiria&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/4/2018	Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/7/2018	The Other Side of the Wind&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/9/2018	They’ll Love Me When I’m Dead&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/10/2018	 Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/18/2018	 Lord of the Rings: Return of the King&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/23/2018	 A Star is Born&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/24/2018	 The Ballad of Buster Scruggs&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/25/2018	 No Country For Old Men&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;11/29/2018	 Ricky Jay and His 52 Assistants&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/2/2018	The Favourite&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/8/2018	At Eternity’s Gate&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/10/2018	 The Price of Everything&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/13/2018	 Rams&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/14/2018	 Logan’s Run&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/16/2018	 Roma&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/18/2018	 The Post&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/20/2018 	Won’t You Be My Neighbor?&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/20/2018	 Happy as Lazzao&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/23/2018	 Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/29/2018	 Downsizing&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/30/2018	 Vice&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/29/2018	 Black Mirror: Bandersnatch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;12/31/2018	 Taylor Swift: The Reputation Stadium Tour&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">1/5/2018 Harry Potter and the Sorcerers Stone 1/6/2018 Harry Potter and the Chamber of Secrets 1/7/2018 Harry Potter and the Prisoner of Azkaban 1/13/2018 Phantom Thread 1/13/2018 Harry Potter and the Goblet of Fire 1/14/2018 Harry Potter and the Order of the Phoenix 1/15/2018 Harry Potter and the Half Blood Prince 1/19/2018 Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows Part I 1/20/2018 Harry Potter and the Deathly Hallows Part 2 1/23/2018 The Visual Language of Herbert Matter 1/26/2018 A Ghost Story 1/28/2018 Get Out 1/30/2018 Kumiku, The Treasure Hunter 1/31/2018 The Founder 2/9/2018 David Bowie: The Last Five Years 2/13/2018 Standup for Drummers 2/16/2018 Wonder Woman 3/2/2018 Fast and Furious 3/3/2018 Black Panther 3/4/2018 Where The Wild Things Are 3/10/2018 Call Me By Your Name 3/11/2018 The War Room 3/12/2018 Annihilation 3/13/2018 Jackie 3/15/2018 Gerhard Richter Painting 3/17/2018 Icarus 3/18/2018 A Wrinkle in Time 3/24/2018 The Death of Stalin 3/28/2018 The Zen Diaries of Garry Shandling 3/31/2018 Isle of Dogs 3/31/2018 Atomic Blonde 4/1/2018 Fantastic Beasts and Where to Find Them 4/7/2018 The Florida Project 4/13/2018 The Cloverfield Paradox 4/13/2018 Seeing Allread 4/14/2018 Gaga: Five Foot Two 4/19/2018 Hidden Figures 4/21/2018 Carol 4/26/2018 Paterno 4/28/2018 The Rachel Divide 4/29/2018 A Quiet Place 5/3/2018 Big Time 5/10/2018 Alps 5/12/2018 Faces Places 5/13/2018 Avengers: Infinity War 5/14/2018 Brad’s Status 5/15/2018 The Killing of a Sacred Deer 5/17/2018 The Fate of the Furious 5/18/2018 Ali Wong: Hard Knock Wife 5/19/2018 Guardians of the Galaxy 5/20/2018 Guardians of the Galaxy Vol. 2 5/22/2018 Dunkirk 5/23/2018 Dogtooth 5/26/2018 Secret Window 5/27/2018 Deadpool 5/28/2018 Deadpool 2 6/7/2018 Coco 6/8/2018 LBJ 6/9/2018 The Final Year 6/10/2018 Solo 6/11/2018 Tokyo Story 6/12/2018 Patty Cake$ 6/14/2018 The Informant! 6/16/2018 Blade Runner 2049 6/17/2018 Ocean’s 8 6/17/2018 Wonder Wheel 6/22/2018 Come Sunday 6/23/2018 Doctor Strange 6/24/2018 Hereditary 6/29/2018 Young Karl Marx 6/29/2018 Hannah Gatsby: Nanette 6/30/2018 Thor 7/2/2018 Fahrenheit 451 7/3/2018 Dick Cavett’s Watergate 7/4/2018 First Reformed 7/4/2018 Thor: The Dark World 7/7/2018 Thor: Ragnarock 7/8/2018 Sorry to Bother You 7/9/2018 What We Do In the Shadows 7/11/2018 Boy 7/14/2018 The Incredibles II 7/15/2018 Eighth Grade 7/15/2018 Marvel’s The Avengers 7/18/2018 The Heretic 7/22/2018 Bo Burnham: Make Happy 7/24/2018 John Mulaney: Kid Gorgeous at Radio City 7/25/2018 Chris Rock: Tambourine 7/25/2018 The Disaster Artist 7/30/2018 Chisholm ‘72: Unbought &amp;amp; Unbossed 8/4/2018 A Girl Walks Home Alone At Night 8/10/2018 Avengers: Age of Ultron 8/11/2018 Ant-Man 8/17/2018 Ex Machina 8/18/2018 Unsane 8/19/2018 Blackkklansman 8/19/2018 Steve Martin &amp;amp; Martin Short: A Night You Will Forget for the Rest of your Life 8/20/2018 Three Billboards Outside Ebbing, Missouri 8/21/2018 Film socialisme 8/22/2018 It 8/24/2018 Hunt for the Wilderpeople 8/25/2018 John McCain: For Whom the Bell Tolls 9/1/2018 Mission: Impossible - Fallout 9/7/2018 To All the Boys I’ve Loved Before 9/9/2018 Battle of the Sexes 9/14/2018 Mother! 9/16/2018 Crazy Rich Asians 9/19/2018 Robin Williams: Come Inside My Mind 9/20/2018 Loving Vincent 9/21/2018 Cargo 10/3/2018 Suburbicon 10/5/2018 The Shape of Water 10/6/2018 Private Life 10/9/2018 The Land of Steady Habits 10/10/2018 Yojimbo 10/11/2018 The Seventh Seal 10/12/2018 Landline 10/31/2018 The Strangers: Prey At Night 11/4/2018 Suspiria 11/4/2018 Lord of the Rings: The Fellowship of the Ring 11/7/2018 The Other Side of the Wind 11/9/2018 They’ll Love Me When I’m Dead 11/10/2018 Lord of the Rings: The Two Towers 11/18/2018 Lord of the Rings: Return of the King 11/23/2018 A Star is Born 11/24/2018 The Ballad of Buster Scruggs 11/25/2018 No Country For Old Men 11/29/2018 Ricky Jay and His 52 Assistants 12/2/2018 The Favourite 12/8/2018 At Eternity’s Gate 12/10/2018 The Price of Everything 12/13/2018 Rams 12/14/2018 Logan’s Run 12/16/2018 Roma 12/18/2018 The Post 12/20/2018 Won’t You Be My Neighbor? 12/20/2018 Happy as Lazzao 12/23/2018 Spider-Man: Into the Spider-Verse 12/29/2018 Downsizing 12/30/2018 Vice 12/29/2018 Black Mirror: Bandersnatch 12/31/2018 Taylor Swift: The Reputation Stadium Tour</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Culture Is Not Always Popular: 15 years of (reading) Design Observer</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/culture-is-not-always-popular/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Culture Is Not Always Popular: 15 years of (reading) Design Observer" /><published>2018-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2018-12-10T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/2018/12/culture-is-not-always-popular</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/2018/12/culture-is-not-always-popular/">&lt;p&gt;Over the last year, I’ve had the privilege of working with Jessica Helfand and Michael Bierut on a new book that is out today by MIT Press: &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2L2jT6D&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;Culture is Not Always Popular: Fifteen Years of Design Observer&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;. The book, which I designed and co-edited, features 66 essays from Design Observer’s history, ranging from the timeless to the timely, the serious to the silly, and opens with a brand new interview I conducted with Michael and Jessica that looks back on the origins of Design Observer and how its evolved over the last decade and a half. I’m proud of the book and can’t wait for you to read it. It was a deeply personal project for me, and one that brings my love of graphic design design full circle.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I found blogs before I found graphic design.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Here’s the scene: An introverted high school student interested in art, architecture, and technology spends his free time designing homes with $40 DIY home design software purchased at a suburban Staples. He fills sketchbooks with drawings and writings, designs his own t-shirts, and begins tinkering with HTML after his family gets high-speed internet. He discovers RSS and starts reading blogs — short for “web log”! — about technology, the internet, and design. On November 2, 2014, he set up a Blogger account of his own and began posting almost daily. He never had many readers but the occasional comment would keep him going. Eventually the blogs he was reading and the topics he was writing about started to coalesce around this thing called &lt;em&gt;graphic design&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;So many of his interests growing up suddenly had a name. His earliest memories looking at letterforms sitting in the front of the shopping cart in the grocery store with his mom? Graphic design. The signs he made to hang in his bedroom windows when he played store in elementary school? Graphic design. The newsletters he designed and edited with his cousins in middle school? Graphic design. The website he designed for the interior design business he started in high school with his friend Andy? Graphic design. He’d taken a career aptitude test at school a few years earlier and right behind architect, ranked graphic designer but it didn’t register. Growing up in the suburbs, he’d never met a graphic designer before. It was blogging that introduced him to this world, blogging that gave his interests a name. And perhaps most importantly, it was blogging that showed him other people were interested in the same things he was.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;He started devouring these blogs, reading them everyday when he’d get home from school. He tried to write like them, borrowing writing styles and responding to topics he found interesting. He subscribed to a lot of them, but his favorite was one called &lt;em&gt;Design Observer&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Design Observer was not the first graphic design blog but it’s one of the few that’s endured. Founded in October 2003 by William Drenntel, Jessica Helfand, Michael Bierut, and Rick Poynor, the site lived up to its tag line, “observations on design and culture,” casting a wide net around their subject matter, posting not just about design, but also about film, politics, books, and art. The posts were thoughtful and researched and the comments were often just as exciting and as interesting. It was not uncommon for those comments to be as well-written and as long as the posts themselves.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;All four of the founders had been involved in the design discourse before: Rick had started &lt;em&gt;Eye Magazine&lt;/em&gt;, Bill and Michael edited the &lt;em&gt;Looking Closer&lt;/em&gt; series, and Jessica had written for a variety of publications and a collection of her essays was released a few years earlier. They had all written for various publications over the last decade. But these mediums were slow — it could be months before an essay came out in print and when it did, you wouldn’t even know if anyone had read it. Blogs changed all that.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Bill and Jessica had decamped to Connecticut from New York City to set up a new studio and they saw blogs as a way to engage in conversation in new ways now that they were removed from the city’s design scene. After recruiting Michael and Rick, Design Observer was born. There was no style guide and no editorial strategy. They wrote about what interested them and they wrote in their own voices. It was accessible and easy to read. As a young designer reading the site, I felt like Michael, Bill, Jessica, and Rick were part of my life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;And as the years passed, they started adding more writers. One thing Design Observer doesn’t get enough credit for, in my opinion, is giving a platform to young designers and critics. For many writers we all know today — Mark Lamster, Alexandra Lange, Alissa Walker, Dori Tunstall — Design Observer was one of the first places they could write; a place to hone their voice and sharpen their gaze.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The magic of Design Observer — and the magic of blogs in general — was the community that was formed around it. Unlike writing for a print publication, you could get immediate feedback. It’s hard to imagine in the toxic comment culture in which we now live, but the comments on Design Observer made for a vibrant — and civil! — community that brought together designers from around the world, from every stage of their career, to discuss, debate, and dissect.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The field was smaller then. Design was still seen as a niche subject. Design Observer was prescient in this regard — they saw design not as something that lives in isolation but something that influences everything around us. This seems obvious now, when every major publication writes about a corporate rebrand and we live in a visually dominated world, but it wasn’t like that fifteen years ago. Design Observer bridged that gap, continually pushing outward and examining design’s role in the world.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As the media landscape changed, so too did Design Observer; the term blog doesn’t feel sufficient anymore. Over the years, they included photo series and link lists, staged conferences and events, set up competitions and published books, and they now produce three podcasts: Design Matters with Debbie Millman and The Observeratory and The Design of Business / The Business of Design, both hosted by Michael and Jessica. As social media slowly took over the comments sections and other blogs began shutting down, the Design Observer podcasts feel like a return to form. The site started as a place for conversation and in a way, the podcast — where we literally listen two people talking to each other in an informal, accessible way — is a distillation of this mission. The more things change, the more they stay the same.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;figure&gt;
    &lt;iframe src=&quot;https://player.vimeo.com/video/299675800?title=0&amp;amp;byline=0&amp;amp;portrait=0&quot; frameborder=&quot;0&quot; allowfullscreen=&quot;&quot;&gt; &lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My interest in graphic design has always run parallel with interests in writing and criticism. My earliest introduction to the field was watching designers write about their work and the work of others on their blogs. As a high student, I understood that part of being a designer was being someone who made work but also thought deeply about that work and its implications in the world. It was only after I was in graduate school studying design criticism — more than ten years after I started reading blogs — that I realized how profound the impact of these blogs had on my own understanding of design. Before studying design in school, before working as a designer, before returning to school, and before I became a teacher myself, there was Design Observer. Along with a handful of other blogs, this was my earliest design education. When I started Scratching the Surface, my podcast about design criticism, some of the first people I reached out to were the people I had been reading on Design Observer for the last fifteen years. The podcast, I guess, is an attempt to recreate that community I saw as a high school student.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;I hope this book is a celebration of that community. It’s a document of a specific era of design history, a record of the community that formed around it, and a time capsule of a blog that had an outsize influence on both the design profession and an introverted kid from Nazareth, Pennsylvania.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;This book would not be possible without the shepherding of Victoria Hindley and everyone at MIT Press, the editorial and administrative assistance of Betsy Vardell and Maya Lim, all the contributors to the site over the last fifteen years, and of course Michael and Jessica.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Reading through the archives as we selected the pieces for the book took me back to those years when this site was my only connection to the graphic design community. I had so much fun rereading so many of these and &lt;a href=&quot;https://amzn.to/2L2jT6D&quot;&gt;hope you enjoy them too&lt;/a&gt;, collected in this volume. It was truly a labor of love. Fifteen year old Jarrett would never believe he got to do this.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><summary type="html">Over the last year, I’ve had the privilege of working with Jessica Helfand and Michael Bierut on a new book that is out today by MIT Press: Culture is Not Always Popular: Fifteen Years of Design Observer. The book, which I designed and co-edited, features 66 essays from Design Observer’s history, ranging from the timeless to the timely, the serious to the silly, and opens with a brand new interview I conducted with Michael and Jessica that looks back on the origins of Design Observer and how its evolved over the last decade and a half. I’m proud of the book and can’t wait for you to read it. It was a deeply personal project for me, and one that brings my love of graphic design design full circle.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Celebrity designers, context collapse, and rethinking how we teach design history</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/projects/celebrity-designers" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Celebrity designers, context collapse, and rethinking how we teach design history" /><published>2018-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2018-10-20T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/projects/context</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/projects/celebrity-designers">&lt;p&gt;My first typography professor loved introducing us to her favorite designers. I remember learning about Paula Scher, Stefan Sagmeister, Milton Glaser, Neville Brody, and David Carson in that class. (She loved David Carson! We saw a lot of his work that semester — this was the mid-2000s, Sagmeister was at the height of his career and the shadow of Carson still loomed.) She wanted us to see work from history, as well as the contemporary work she found exciting so that it could inspire, inform, and guide our own work. Looking at the earliest work I did in school, you can see what designers had caught my interest at various points in my undergraduate career: the Vignelli phase came first, then it was Pentagram. By junior year, I was interested in illustration, and my work looked like Charley Harper's and Frank Chimero's. I had an infographic phase inspired by Nicholas Felton and an embarrassing handlettering period that mostly resulted in bad Jessica Hische knock-offs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;My classmates were the same way. There was a group of us who closely followed design blogs, tracking the 'celebrity designers' of the time. Some of us even got really excited by the two required design history surveys, saving images to our pre-Pinterest inspiration files and trying on the styles of different designers likes costumes. I remember one student particularly well who, following the lecture on Art Nouveau, decided he was going to make every project look like an Alphonse Mucha poster for the rest of the semester. I still cringe at the Russian-Constructivist-inspired poster I designed for a school function. We named dropped in critiques, showing off with our knowledge of history or our awareness of the trendy designers of the moment, completely unaware that half the class was rolling their eyes. For myself and my friends, it felt like part of being a good designer was knowing those names.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When I found myself back in the classroom — nearly a decade later, this time as the teacher — I was surprised to find how many of my students, at every level, had little sense of the history of graphic design, not to mention the 'celebrity designers' of today. Design history is largely foreign to them; it's an optional course in many design programs. It's rare for a student to know Sagmeister, Carson, and Scher (or Rudnick, Hu, and Walsh) if I mention one in class. I once had an upper level student who had never heard of Pentagram. &lt;em&gt;Pentagram!&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It's not that this generation of designers isn't consuming design media but the way they do is wildly different than when I was in school. At their age, we read blogs to find out who was doing the most interesting work, but those don't exist anymore. My students aren't reading It's Nice That or Eye on Design. They are on Instagram, on Behance, on Pinterest. Their design awareness, sensibilities, and taste is constructed through likes, pins, and retweets. They might not know the name Michael Bierut or have heard of Wolff Olins but they've seen the work. And they've also seen work from countless other designers flying below the mainstream design press radar.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consuming design this way creates a peculiar context collapse. Everything moves fast, the thumb occasionally pausing for a closer look, where work from an international branding agency can sit next to a great poster by a high school student in India. These images travel from board to board, retweet to retweet, ever so slowly removing any sense of where it came from — the designer is often anonymous, the subject matter irrelevant. A quick tap saves it and then it's on to the next image. My students don't know the names of designers or agencies or studios but they do know what's trending, the popular styles, and the latest rebrand. Eventually, all the work starts to look the same.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Kids these days&lt;/em&gt;, I caught myself thinking. I had become the cranky old man complaining about how the next generation doesn't understand it sooner than I had thought I would. I mean, I'm only thirty and here I was worried about what this meant for the future. &lt;em&gt;It was better when I was in school,&lt;/em&gt; I thought.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But what if this isn't necessarily a bad thing? Maybe this is an opportunity to teach design history and culture another way. Maybe it's a good thing for the idea of the 'celebrity designer' to die. The myth of the solo genius, alone in his studio, doesn't work anymore, and far too often it continues to only elevate the white male designer. Design conferences continue to feature the same designers year after year, sometimes even when at least one of those designers probably &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.nzherald.co.nz/business/news/article.cfm?c_id=3&amp;amp;objectid=11804042&quot;&gt;deserves to be cancelled&lt;/a&gt;. This perpetuates a particular idea of what a successful designer looks like and what makes for 'good design'.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Whether intended or not, the images my undergraduate professors showed us became the standard by which we judged design, and the names attached subconsciously became the people we were supposed to be emulating. The design history courses I took a decade ago were surveys: the professor would click through images on the screen in the front of the room; a list of names and styles we had to memorize. We spent little time talking about the content or articulating the context it sits within. Like my students now, I would get excited by something else I saw and use it in my own projects, regardless of context or content. Where we knew names, they know styles. Is one of these really worse than the other?&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To be clear: this is not to say that names shouldn't be attached to the work or that we should disregard history. I believe these to be important elements of any design education. But &lt;em&gt;inspiration&lt;/em&gt; is not enough. Trends are not enough. Simply collecting images is not enough. To move beyond inspiration, to dig deeper than trends and avoid celebrity design culture, we must make space for our students to reflect on this work and think about how it connects to their own blossoming practices.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every class I teach, at both the undergraduate and graduate level, I've started requiring students to keep a visual journal — a dedicated place to keep images, PDFs, videos, photos — a simple attempt to encourage them to be more thoughtful about what they are consuming and saving. I try to build time into class for students to reflect on the work they are finding, and at the same time, I'm sharing the things I'm looking at and thinking about. (And I make it clear that what I share isn't always an endorsement.) Together we try to figure out why we are drawn to these things. Or repulsed by them. Or why they are trending. Or where they come from. We talk as a group about art movements and trends and gaps in history. We lean into the aesthetics, the contexts, the politics, and the ideologies that may or may not be embedded in the work. We dissect the visual moves the designer did and why she may have made those decisions. We find out more about the designer, of course, but we let the work speak for itself. Just because it came from a particular designer or a particular studio doesn't mean it's automatically great. Some of the best moments I've had in the classroom are when the students start debating these ideas — amongst themselves, without any guidance from me — trying to formulate their own point of view.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I want to create a space for young designers to feel comfortable conducting a thoughtful interrogation of images, visual culture, and the very profession they are about to enter — perhaps a small step in dismantling the celebrity designer complex while moving beyond the trends of their time. Looking at other design will always be central to the young designer's process, but they should't feel bound to trends, to styles, to celebrity as they move through their careers. The problem isn't that students don't know designers' names or are blindly following trends, it's that it is all moving too fast. Instead of fighting the new consumption paradigms, I've started to embrace it. Where I once looked down on these new modes of consuming media, romanticizing my own college experience, I now see the design students today as better equipped to do this work than I was at their age. They are well-versed in reading images, fluent in media literacy, and far less interested in celebrity. They get to experience more design — from all across the world — than any previous generation. If any of us can move beyond celebrity and dig deeper than the latest trend, it is them. We just need to be sure they have the critical tools, along with space and time, to do this work. The kids, I'm beginning to think, will be alright. ✖&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="[&quot;Teaching&quot;, &quot;Design&quot;]" /><summary type="html">My first typography professor loved introducing us to her favorite designers. I remember learning about Paula Scher, Stefan Sagmeister, Milton Glaser, Neville Brody, and David Carson in that class. (She loved David Carson! We saw a lot of his work that semester — this was the mid-2000s, Sagmeister was at the height of his career and the shadow of Carson still loomed.) She wanted us to see work from history, as well as the contemporary work she found exciting so that it could inspire, inform, and guide our own work. Looking at the earliest work I did in school, you can see what designers had caught my interest at various points in my undergraduate career: the Vignelli phase came first, then it was Pentagram. By junior year, I was interested in illustration, and my work looked like Charley Harper's and Frank Chimero's. I had an infographic phase inspired by Nicholas Felton and an embarrassing handlettering period that mostly resulted in bad Jessica Hische knock-offs.</summary></entry></feed>